<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: CoffeeScript | Luan Santos]]></title>
  <link href="http://luan.github.com/categories/coffeescript/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://luan.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-07-13T15:11:08-03:00</updated>
  <id>http://luan.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luan Santos]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[luan@luansantos.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Ember FormBuilder]]></title>
    <link href="http://luan.github.com/2012/03/19/introducing-ember-formbuilder/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-19T14:36:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://luan.github.com/2012/03/19/introducing-ember-formbuilder</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>I was hacking around with Ember.js and had to do a kind of complex form.
All fields were bound to one object and I had a hard time styling and binding everything.
While doing this I got myself thinking of <a href="https://github.com/plataformatec/simple_form">simple_form</a>
and how it would be helping me if I could use it.</p>

<p>And why not create a form builder for Ember? Yeah why not, I decided to try. I can't say I failed
miserably because the idea is cool, I like what I wrote in the <a href="https://github.com/luan/ember-formbuilder/blob/master/README.md">README</a>
and how things are defined to work. But no doubt the code ended up a pile of crap,
complicated, hard to understand and hard to evolve from.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>This post is about the idea. And to tell you guys that I will now rewrite it (yeah I know,
I'm rewriting a project that has what, 2 days life? But one should fail ASAP).</p>

<p>Any help is appreciated, I'm really new to testing javascript (and to testing at all)
but I'm finding my way in that. Now let's talk about the form builder.</p>

<h1>Ember FormBuilder</h1>

<p>Based on simple_form primarily Ember FormBuilder aims to be the toolkit to build from basic to
complex forms that binds automatically to your ember objects. It's really customizable by just
defining a mixin with your markup definitions, just like this:</p>

<p><code>coffeescript
Bootstrap = Ember.Mixin.create
  wrapperTag: 'div'
  wrapperClass: 'control-group'
  inputWrapperTag: 'div'
  inputWrapperClass: 'controls'
  labelClass: 'control-label'
  helpTag: 'p'
  helpClass: 'help-block'
  errorTag: 'span'
  errorClass: 'help-inline'
  formClass: 'form-vertical'
  submitClass: 'btn btn-success'
  cancelClass: 'btn btn-danger'
Ember.FormBuilder.pushMixin(Bootstrap, "bootstrap")
</code></p>

<p>If you are familiar to simple_form syntax the handlebars helpers we define will be just the
thing you were looking for. You can define a form with <code>{{#formFor "object"}}</code> and define
imputs with <code>{{input "name"}}</code>. As simple as that. You can find out more about it by reading
the <a href="https://github.com/luan/ember-formbuilder/blob/master/README.md">README</a> on github.</p>

<p>There is also support for some kind of internationalization, I say somekind because you
set an object <code>Ember.FormBuilder.STRINGS</code> with some string values (again refer to README
here) and you have to work your way to make it internationalized in there, it's something
to be thought further later, but that's another subject for another time.</p>

<h1>Ok</h1>

<p>Yeah I mean, that's the whole thing. I just wanted to show that. I will rewrite it now
using decent patterns and making things more reusable and easier to understand. Will
write decent unit tests and integration tests too, currently there is just a bunch of
weird tests that I don't belive that covers much of it.</p>

<p>The code is in github <a href="https://github.com/luan/ember-formbuilder">here</a> and if you
have time and want to help I would be delighted. Of course, read the README and
point out flaws if you see some.</p>

<p>Thanks for reading, good bye.</p>

<p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Using Facebook JS SDK with Ember.js]]></title>
    <link href="http://luan.github.com/2012/03/06/using-facebook-js-sdk-with-emberjs/"/>
    <updated>2012-03-06T10:25:00-03:00</updated>
    <id>http://luan.github.com/2012/03/06/using-facebook-js-sdk-with-emberjs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p>This is my first blog post and it will be as simple as that.</p>

<h3>Using the ember-facebook library</h3>

<p>I wrote a (<em>really</em>) simples addon for <a href="http://www.emberjs.com">Ember.js</a> to automatically load the <a href="https://developers.facebook.com/docs/reference/javascript/">facebook javascript sdk</a>, it's called <a href="http://www.github.com/luan/ember-facebook">ember-facebook</a> as you'd expect.</p>

<p>To use it you just have to download the compiled js file from the downloads page on the github repository. The library is written in <a href="http://coffeescript.org">CoffeeScript</a> and I do <a href="http://arcturo.github.com/library/coffeescript/">love CoffeeScript</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/downloads/luan/ember-facebook/ember-facebook.js">Download ember-facebook.js</a></p>

<p>Once you done it include it right after the actual Ember.js file, and before your application one, do it as you are used to.</p>

<p>Right now you can use it like this, on your application creation include the Facebook Mixin:</p>

<p><code>coffeescript Application Configuration
App = Em.Application.create(Em.Facebook)
App.set 'appId', 'YourAppId'
</code></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>And it will graciously load the Facebook JS SDK for you, you don't have to do anything else. Now you are able to use the <code>FB</code> object to call Facebook's API, and we assigned a FBUser to your App to reffer to the logged in user.
If you want a login button you can do something like this:</p>

<p>```html Simple login/logout buttons
{{#if App.FBUser}}
  <div></p>

<pre><code>&lt;img {{bindAttr src="App.FBUser.picture" alt="App.FBUser.name"}} /&gt;
{{App.FBUser.name}}
&lt;a href="#" {{action "logout" target="FB"}}&gt;Logout&lt;/a&gt;
</code></pre>

<p>  </div>
{{else}}
  {{#view Em.FacebookView type="login-button" data-size="xlarge"</p>

<pre><code>                      data-scope="email, offline_access"}}
Connect
</code></pre>

<p>  {{/view}}
{{/if}}
```</p>

<p>Note that we are checking for the existance of App.FBUser and then displaying the user names and picture together with a logout link if the user is present OR we show a custom view called FacebookView that basically creates a view of the Facebook SDK, you can check more on their documentation.</p>

<p>Basically we create a button with the xlarge size and ask for the scopes "email" and "offline_access" with the content "Connect".</p>

<p>You can customize it however. You could either create a link to that, just bindint the action "login" to the target "FB" (as we did with logout).</p>

<h3>Creating the ember-facebook library</h3>

<p>The <a href="https://github.com/luan/ember-facebook/blob/master/src/ember-facebook.coffee">sources</a> for the library are really really simple. I basically observes the "appId" attribute and when that changes it loads the Facebook JS SDK for that app.</p>

<p>Whenever the user changes (login, logout, app authorization, etc) the method <code>updateFBUser</code> is called, updating the App.FBUser object on your application. You can do whatever you want with this binding, observe it, put it in the DOM, whatever.</p>

<p>We also have a App.FBloading binding which is a boolean that basically tells that we are waiting a facebook response.</p>

<p>You might want to show something based on this:</p>

<p><code>html Fancy Loading
{{#if App.FBloading}}
  &lt;div class="my-fancy-loading"&gt;Waiting for Facebook&lt;/div&gt;
{{/if}}
</code></p>

<h3>That's all folks</h3>

<p>I hope you like it, as it being my first post it might look retarded, but I hope it was helpful for someone.</p>

<p>See ya!</p>

<p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
