<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Vim | Luan Santos]]></title>
  <link href="http://luan.github.com/categories/vim/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://luan.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-09T02:05:31-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://luan.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Luan Santos]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[luan@luansantos.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You Are Using Your Editor Wrong]]></title>
    <link href="http://luan.github.com/2012/08/01/you-are-using-your-editor-wrong/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-01T21:57:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://luan.github.com/2012/08/01/you-are-using-your-editor-wrong</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p></p>

<p><em>And the wrong editor!</em></p>

<p>You always hear people saying their editor is the best, that everyone should use
it and bla bla bla. I do that myself, Vim is the best, you should use it.</p>

<p>You also hear "you should do <em>xx</em> this way, you will be more productive". And
then your hear back from the other side "nah, it doesn't matter, use anything,
anyway, it will do the same job".</p>

<p>Everyone has opinions about this, and I want to analyze it and give mine.</p>

<p><em>And you are not doing anything wrong, in fact, you are absolutely correct!</em></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I seriously don't think anyone is right, or wrong. It really depends on the
person. I read an article about switching to Vim by the awesome Yehuda Katz (he
is really awesome) stating that you should just open Vim and use it like a
conventional editor (arrow keys, mouse, etc)
<a href="http://yehudakatz.com/2010/07/29/everyone-who-tried-to-convince-me-to-use-vim-was-wrong/">the article</a>.</p>

<p>That could have worked for him, and it has definitely worked for some of my
friends also, but not for me, I had to follow the regular path of doing
everything the vim way, disable arrow keys, disable mouse, and FORCE me to do
everything on the way that Vim wanted me to do.</p>

<h1>Where Am I At The Text Editing World</h1>

<p>I am a Vim user, I use Vim for everything, I have Vim bindings on my Chrome, I
love that the official OSX twitter client has Vim bindings, I love that Gmail
and Sparrow (RIP) have it too. I don't know how to navigate anything without <code>j</code>
and <code>k</code>.</p>

<p>I consider myself good at Vim, I use Vim modal editing to extreme, I am not one
of those guys you get astonished when you see typing, tho.</p>

<p>I have used plenty of text editors and IDEs in my life. Including Aptana (Rad
Rails), Textmate, Red Car, Sublime Text 2, Chocolat, Emacs, etc. I have
opinions about all of them, and wouldn't feel unconfortable if I had to use some
of the again (although there are some that I'd rather use a naked vi instead).</p>

<h1>And What The Heck Is Your Opinion?</h1>

<p>Each person has needs and preferences, and everyone is different, everyone has
it's own "soul mate" text editor. And while I do belive the text editor can
affect the coding speed I don't think it is significant to justify a text
editor switch. <a href="http://lateral.netmanagers.com.ar/weblog/posts/your-editor-is-not-the-bottleneck.html">This guys</a>
opinion is really valid and I agree in the most part.</p>

<p>You should choose your editor based on your personal preferences (and I bet my
kidney you are already doing it). For some it must be beautiful (a lot of
people switch to OS X because it's beautiful), for some it must be dead simple,
for some it should be platform independent.</p>

<p>The part I disagree from that post is that you can code in anything, even in
kwrite. Even though you CAN, that really depends on the coder needs, I for
example, NEED <code>ctags</code> and some sort of file jumping good. That given author does
not need anything, so he can code in anything that accepts keyboard input and
maybe has some syntax highlighting.</p>

<h1>What I Am Trying To Say</h1>

<p>I am trying to say that you can't be wrong if you are getting your job done. If
you feel like you can feel better on a different editor, or with more plugins,
or on a massively slow crazy IDE then just go for it. People will always
advocate for their own preferences and you can't be judged for using something
like kwrite, or eclipse, or emacs, or whatever (even though you will be), just
get your job done right and good using the tools you feel more confortable
with.</p>

<p>Explore your possibilities, I think everyone should give Vim and Emcas a try.
Both are awesome and have some different ways of doing things. Vims modal
editing and macros will blow your mind. And Emacs control-driven commands will
make your finger hurt. If you are on OS X you should take a look on Coda and
Chocolat, they have such a cute UI.</p>

<p>I want to finish this by listing my favorite pieces of work on text editing:</p>

<ul>
<li>Vim (MacVim)</li>
<li>Sublime Text 2</li>
<li>Chocolat</li>
<li>Textmate</li>
<li>Emacs</li>
<li>Gedit</li>
</ul>


<p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
